which hormones affect Direction quality
besides testosterone
okay
prolactin is a big
one a deficiency of estrad is a big one
often caused by two primary causes one
aromatase Inhibitors or the disruption
of aromatization via other forms or two
a low state testostrone in a male which
then leads to inability to aromatize
sufficiently so low estrad too much
prolactin or too little
prolactin uh and then we get into uh uh
um
adrenaline okay adrenaline leads
to uh acute hypertension which will
destroy an erection uh althetic loads
which is a chronic state of adrenal
overload which leads to chronic
hypertension which will destroy
erections
then we get into nonsteroid hormones
like insulin hyper insulin which leads
to insulin resistance which leads to
thicker blood which leads to erectile
dysfunction so we can go down this
rabbit hole into all of the things that
lead to erectile dysfunction from a
physiological standpoint Now understand
that 75% of erection quality once the
physiological aspect has been addressed
is psychological so you have the
psychogenic side and you have the
physiologic side and both must
intertwine in order for equality
erection to occur so as much as I love
the field of hormones and the
intricacies that come with it the sexual
medical side is significantly more
complex and I enjoy that a lot as well
but it is not a quick and simple
assessment we usually do 45 minutes to
an hour of conversation with an erectile
dysfunction patient to really get to the
root cause you have to understand we
don't accept
idiopathic
diagnosis before we treat we have to
pinpoint a cause and we don't like the
empirical way of treating and just
throwing everything at the kitchen sink
and hoping that something sticks we
really want to get down to the
nitty-gritty of what caused the problem